Nicholas Russo

1-925-699-1715 | nijaru0x@gmail.com | https://nijaru.com

SUMMARY

I am a software developer from California interested in distributed systems, linux. networking, and security. I have used Go, Python, Ruby, Javascript, C, and C++. I am also learning Rust and a little Clojure.

I mainly use Fedora along with MacOS, Debian, and Ubuntu. I also have some experience with Gentoo, Container Linux, Alpine, and VyOS. My current projects include using Rust and Go for systems and networking projects and diving into Linux internals.

PROJECTS & AWARDS

Networking with Go

Implementing a networking stack in Go. The end goal is to use it as a router at home and deploy it on my Ubiquiti Edgerouter X in place of EdgeOS.

Container Runtime

Writing my a container runtime in Rust to learn more about containers, rust, and linux.

Part Time Job Board

Creating a job board focused on local, hourly positions to help small businesses find and hire new candidates. I plan to launch, monetize, and advertise the site.

Kairos - 2nd Place & Ingenico Team Winner - Money20/20 Hackathon - October 2016 Built a cross-terminal payment application and API for partnering businesses together. I built a Go/PostgreSQL API and deployed it on top of Container Linux.

Crime.ly - Hack Against Violence Hackathon - September 2016

Led a weekend hackathon team to build an interactive website that provides a map of crime occurring in SF using Javascript and Google Maps.

Omnipass - Blockchain Virtual GovHack - December 2016

MySQL

PostgreSQL

Built an identity management system on top of the Ethereum Network.

Cycle The Bay - May 2016

An iOS app that provides users with trails, elevation, distance, weather, and navigation. I built a Rails/PostgreSQL API for the mobile app.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Support Technician Robert Half June 2011 - December 2011 IT Intern City of Pleasanton January 2010 - May 2010

EDUCATION

Las Positas College, Livermore, CA — Computer Science — 2014 - 2015, 2016 - 2018 Computer Science Club President — Fall 2016 - Spring 2017 42 Silicon Valley, Fremont, CA — 2018 - 2019

SKILLS

 Go Python

 Rubv Redis Javascript GraphQL

• C/C++ Git Rails Docker Kubernetes

Debian/Ubuntu

Fedora/CentOS

 <u>AWS</u> Google Cloud

• Bash

DigitalOcean

Vim

 Heroku TravisCl

• Cloudflare

• Zsh